给你
There you go.
谢谢
Thanks.
爆炸了
An explosion!
这些炮火来自空中吗
Is this incoming artillery fire from above?
不  隆美尔的军团将我们的将士引入了雷区
No! Rommel's troops have lured our boys into a minefield.
那么M4谢尔曼坦克的装甲是否能抵挡
Will the m-4 Sherman tank's armor be able to withstand
来自下方的懦弱的弹幕呢
this cowardly barrage from below?
是的  可以
Yes, it can!
谢尔曼坦克突破了纳粹防线来到
And the Sherman smashes through Nazi lines to reach the...
哇  这可不是苏伊士运河
Whoa. That is not the Suez Canal.
如果你在决定穿什么
If you're trying to decide what to wear,
别再多穿就好
just keep wearing what you're wearing now...
少穿也行
Or less.
变态
Pervert.
变态的是陆军元帅
That is Field Marshal pervert to you.
卡塞尔  你能接下吗
Castle, can you grab that?
好的
Got it.
贝克特探长办公室
This is Detective Beckett's office.
真的吗  汽车炸弹
Seriously? A car bomb?
警力不少啊
Talk about a heightened police presence.
等等  这是怎么回事
Wait a minute. What is this?
不对劲  埃斯波
Something's not right. Hey, Espo.
为什么把车运走
Why are they taking the car away?
鉴证组还没有取证完吧
C.S.U.'s not done with it, is it?
几乎还没开始
They were barely started
联邦探员就来查封了车辆
before the Feds came in and seized the vehicle.
他们为什么查封车辆
Why would they seize the vehicle?
我问了  但人家不搭理我
I tried to ask, but they iced me out.
谁负责
Who's in charge?
看到那边那个没
See that guy over there?
格雷罗探员
Name's agent Guerrero.
相信我  他不会让步的
Trust me. He's not gonna budge.
格雷罗探员
Agent Guerrero.
我是贝克特探长
I'm Detective Beckett--
不用劳烦你了  这车我们要带走
Let me save you the trouble. We're taking the car.
鉴证组还没有完成取证
C.S.U. hasn't finished processing it yet.
这是凶杀现场
This is a murder scene.
我得确认被害人身份
I'm gonna need to find out who the victim was--
抱歉  那辆车属于联邦案件调查范围
I'm sorry, but that vehicle's part of a federal investigation.
如果你们有任何阻挠
And if you people hinder us in any way,
我们会以妨碍公务罪名逮捕你们
we'll arrest you for obstruction.
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell's going on here?
为什么国家安全局的也来了
And why is Homeland Security involved?
不知道  这事很蹊跷
I don't know. This whole thing stinks.
据目击证人说
According to witnesses,
那边两个人在爆炸前  就一直在监视车辆
those two guys were staking out the car even before it blew up,
国家安全局的人不让我和他们谈话
And Homeland Security isn't letting me talk to them.
神秘的汽车炸弹
A mysterious car bombing...
联邦探员给我们吃闭门羹
The Feds giving us the boot,
现在又有了黑衣人
and now men in black.
我得说  我很好奇
I'll say it. I'm intrigued.
你们是什么人
Who are you guys?
表明身份
Identify yourselves.
两位  经常有人这么说吧
Hey, guys. You get this a lot--
J探员  K探员
Agent "J," Agent "K"?
你们为什么要监视那辆车
Why were you guys surveilling that car?
爆炸时谁在车上
Who was in it when it exploded?
没有尸体
Well, we don't have a body,
没有犯罪现场
we don't have a crime scene,
没有任何目击证人  但是
and we don't have any witnesses, but...
至少我们还拥有彼此
At least we have each other.
-我们依然有件凶杀案要破  -还有这个
- We still have a homicide to solve. - And that.
看来知道死者身份了
I think I got an I.D. on our vic.
警员发现了他的钱包
A uniform... found his wallet,
被炸飞了半条街
blown about a half a block down that way.
外貌与目击者看到的
Matches the description of the guy
进入车辆的人相符
that witnesses saw get in the car.
死者叫戴尔·坦纳
His name is Dale Tanner.
我一直知道会有这一天
I always knew this day might come.
戴尔也知道  这是他工作的危害之一
Dale did, too. It was one of the hazards of his job.
什么样的工作会导致这种结果
What kind of a job would lead to this?
戴尔16岁时
When Dale was 16,
他的父亲在德州被判杀人罪名成立
his father was convicted of murder in Texas--
他父亲是冤枉的
wrongly convicted.
在复审前  他父亲死在了监狱里
Right before the retrial, his father died in prison.
所以为弱势群体而战
And so fighting for the underdog, that...
成了他的人生目标
kind of became his life's mission.
大约十年前  他创建了一个网站
So about ten years ago he started the web site.
匿名告密者
"Whistleblower anonymous."
我知道这个网站
I know that site.
他曝光了水刑备忘录
He exposed the, uh, the waterboarding memos,
还有奥顿公司水力压裂公司丑闻
the Orton-geo fracking scandal.
我不知道网站的创办人居然是他
I had no idea he was the one behind it.
戴尔觉得比起自己的安危
Dale felt it was more important
让大众一直关注这些问题更重要
to keep attention on the issues rather than himself.
你丈夫最近在调查什么吗
Was your husband working on anything recently?
有  我想他计划公布一些文件
Yeah, I think he was planning on posting some documents.
不管是什么  令他很紧张
Whatever they were, they were making him nervous.
文件现在在哪里
Where are the documents now?
可能在皇后区他的律师事务所里
Probably at his law office in Queens.
为什么国家安全局的人  对你的丈夫有兴趣
Why would Homeland Security be interested in your husband?
政府一半的人都对我的丈夫有兴趣
Half the government was interested in my husband.
他公布了阿布格莱布监狱虐待伊拉克战俘的照片后
After he posted those photographs of Abu Ghraib,
他们就想让他说出信息来源
they... tried to get him to reveal his sources.
他们骚扰他
They harassed him.
他去哪里都被跟踪
Followed him everywhere he went.
情况糟糕到两个月前
It got so bad that, two months ago,
他搬到了我们在皇后区的租赁公寓
he actually moved into our rental unit in Queens.
他说他担心我们的安全问题
He said that he was concerned about our safety.
现在他死了
And now he's dead.
坦纳太太
Mrs. Tanner,
目击证人说你丈夫把车停在默瑟街
Witnesses say that your husband parked on Mercer
就在八点之前
just before 8:00.
在人行道上等到八点十五分
Waited on the sidewalk till 8:15,
然后回到车上
and then he got back in his car.
你知道他在市区做什么吗
Do you know what he was doing downtown?
不知道
I have no idea.
他觉得  我们知道的越少越好
He felt like, the less we knew, the better.
我应该经常找他聊聊的
I should've talked to him more.
他有没有同事
Did he work with anyone else
可能知道他卷入了什么事件
that might have known what he was involved in?
他有个搭档
He had a partner,
但我不知道是谁
but... I don't know who it was.
我们为什么要理他们  妈
Why are we even talking to them, mom?
政府杀了我的父亲
The government killed my father,
你们在帮助政府掩盖事实
and you're helping them cover it up.
肖恩  别这样
Sean, please.
我不会管这种行为叫掩盖事实
Now I'm not gonna call this a cover-up,
但我得说  联邦探员可没有帮我们
but I will say this-- the Feds are not helping us out.
他们不肯透露在坦纳的车上找到了什么证据
They won't tell us what evidence they found in Tanner's car.
好吧  那我们就换个角度着手
Okay. So we'll just work it from other angles.
我们知道他有个搭档
We know that he had a partner.
不如不查查他的手机记录
Why don't we look into his phone records,
看看是谁
see who it was?
因为我们还不被允许查这个
Because they're not being released to us.
坦纳的财务状况也查不到
Neither are Tanner's financials.
也许可以在他的律师事务所查到
Maybe we can get it from his law office?
我们想搜查那里
We tried to search there.
他们已经封了办公室  拿走了他的电脑
They sealed the place and they took his computers.
我开始明白你说联邦探员不会帮忙的意思了
I'm starting to see what you mean by the feds not helping.
那我们只能自己解决这案子  不用他们帮忙
Then we're just gonna solve this without their help.
动机查的怎么样了
Where are we on motive?
这个倒是不少
Well, there's plenty of that to go around.
坦纳不怕得罪大人物
Tanner wasn't afraid to take on the big boys--
银行家  石油巨头  腐败的政治家
Banks, big oil, dirty politicians.
去年  他揭露了极具毁灭性
In the past year, he posted highly damaging,
我得加一句
and I might add,
而且真实的信息  涉及30家企业
truthful information on 30 corporations,
政府部门或个人
government agencies, and individuals.
这还是我在他的网站
And that's just what I found
被关闭前找到的凤毛麟角
before his site was taken off-line.
没有确切的信息
With no solid information,
我们根本无法入手
it's hard to even know where to start.
从死亡方式开始吧
We start with manner of death.
我们要查的是炸弹
We know we're dealing with a bomb,
这枚炸弹被安在坦纳的车里
a bomb that was already in Tanner's car.
对  如果他在这辆车附近
Right, because he stayed near the vehicle,
就没人能去动手脚
no one could've tampered with it.
安置炸弹的人肯定是在
And whoever planted the bomb had to have
早些时候接触到了车
access to the car at an earlier point.
比如在他的车库里
Like in his garage.
坦纳把车开到城里前  车就在车库
That's where the car was before Tanner drove it downtown,
我找邻居了解了一下情况
and when I talked to the neighbors,
有人看到今天凌晨一点
one of them saw an unfamiliar motorcycle
有辆陌生的摩托车开出了车库
jet out of the garage last night at 1:00 a.m.
他们看到车牌了没
Did they happen to get a plate?
没有
No.
但监控录像里有
But this traffic cam did.
摩托登记在一个位莫妮卡·莱恩名下
Bike's registered to a Monica Lane.
她是个安保承包商
And get this--she works as a security contractor
在奥顿公司工作
at orton-geo.
那就是那个差点被坦纳
That's the fracking company
搞垮的水力压裂公司
Tanner almost put out of business.
镜头还真是会把人拍胖了
Man, the camera really does add 10 pounds.
你被拍到前  刚从一个公寓楼停车库出来
You were coming from an apartment building garage before that was taken.
你在那里做什么
What were you doing there?
不关你们的事
That's none of your business.
戴尔·坦纳被炸得粉身碎骨  就与我们有关了
It became our business when Dale Tanner got blown to bits.
什么  他死了
What? He's dead?
对  而且我猜贵公司听到这消息
Yeah, and I bet the company that you work for
一定欢欣雀跃
likes him a whole lot better that way.
我和他的死毫无干系
Look, I had nothing to do with his death.
事情不是你们想的那样
This is not what you think.
那是怎么回事  莫妮卡
Then what is it, Monica?
我和他在约会
He and I were seeing each other.
是吗
Really?
你和戴尔·坦纳
You and Dale Tanner?
我们几个月前在公园认识的
We met in the park a few months ago.
一拍即合
We just connected.
可不是  看得出你很受伤
Yeah. I can see you're real busted up.
你在刺探他
You were spying on him.
你接近他就是为了这个吧
Isn't that what this is really about?
奥顿公司因为戴尔·坦纳损失了
Okay, orton-geo lost half a billion dollars in contracts
五个亿的合约
because of Dale Tanner.
我的任务是接近他
My job was to get close to him
找出是谁在给他提供信息
and find out who was leaking him information.
但绝对没说要杀了他
But it did not involve killing him.
还有其他人盯着他吗  除了你
Was anyone else after him? Besides you, of course.
老天啊
Oh, God.
他的妻子
His wife.
他说她打过电话  说发现我俩的事了
He said she had called. She'd just found out about us.
她威胁要杀了他
She threatened to kill him.
我觉得受到了背叛
I felt betrayed.
你明白吗
Don't you see?
我支持了他24年
I-I stood by him for 24 years.
你之前对他有外遇的事保密
You withheld that he was having an affair,
然后又费尽心思
and then you went out of your way
装出他因工作而丧命的样子
to make it look like his work got him killed.
他就是因为工作才死的
Because it did.
好  我承认
All right, look, I admit it. Okay?
我确实威胁过戴尔  但我当时很生气
I said some things to Dale, but I was upset.
另外  我根本没去过他的公寓附近
Besides, I didn't go near that apartment. I didn't.
你可以雇人动手
You could've hired someone else to do it.
钱从哪来
With what money, huh?
真是的
Really?
戴尔那个网站可不是摇钱树
It's not like Dale and his web site ever made anybody rich.
贝克特  你得过来看看
Beckett, there's something you need to see.
这是鉴证组送过来的
So, um... C.S.U. sent this over.
他们掌握的线索不多
Based on what little they had,
但还是还原了起爆点
they were able to piece together where the explosion originated.
我要大胆猜测一下
I'm gonna go out on a limb here
我认为炸弹是在他的车里引爆的
and say the explosion originated in the car.
通常  在车上安装炸弹
Right. Well, normally, a car bomb is placed
会安在发动机舱里面或下面
inside the engine compartment or underneath.
但这个是在靠近前排座位的地方引爆的
But this one went off near the front seat.
确实是安装在车里的
So it was planted inside the car.
事实上根本不是安在那儿的
Actually, it wasn't planted at all.
鉴证组找到了这些金属碎片
C.S.U. found these metal fragments,
并且查明这是一种很特别的装置
and they were able to trace it to a very specific device.
他们将其拼凑起来
They put together this...
重现了爆炸过程
reconstruction of the explosion.
那是导弹吗
Is that a missile?
具体来说  这种导弹
Specifically, the kind of missile
是从无人机发射的
deployed from an unmanned aerial vehicle.
戴尔·坦纳是被无人机杀死的
Dale Tanner was taken out by a drone?
戴尔·坦纳前一秒还坐在车里
One second Dale Tanner's sitting in his car.
后一秒  嘭
The next... boom.
可怜的家伙  都不知道自己被什么击中了
Poor guy didn't even know what hit him.
无人机怎么会攻击他
This couldn't have been a drone strike.
肯定是哪里弄错了
There's gotta be a mistake here.
没弄错
There isn't.
鉴证组发现了PBXN-112爆炸残留物
C.S.U. found PBXN-112 explosive residue
以及导弹外壳的氟化铝成分
and fluoridated aluminum from a missile casing.
军用无人机不可能
There's no way that a military drone
这么明目张胆地飞过纽约上空  丢下导弹
could fly over New York city and smoke a guy.
其实是可以的
Actually, it could.
在蒙德堡有个无人机训练基地
There's a drone training facility at Fort Drummond.
莱恩  我和卡塞尔去查这个线索
Ryan, while Castle and I look into that,
你去找认识坦纳的人聊聊
can you talk to anyone that knew Tanner?
看看能否查出他的搭档是谁
Let's see if we can find out who his partner was.
你和卡塞尔去蒙德堡
What, you and Castle are going to Fort Drummond?
无人机项目的负责人同意见我们了
Yeah, the head of the drone program agreed to a meeting.
到底怎么回事
What is going on here?
你认为是军队把他干掉的吗
Do you really think the military took him out?
我觉得他们不能这么做
I don't see how they could.
因为不能越界吗
Because they wouldn't cross that line?
据我的经验来看
Because in my experience,
庞大的官僚系统没那么效率
huge bureaucracies don't act with that kind of efficiency.
这话倒是令人安心
Well, that's comforting.
你没什么军工企业的疯狂阴谋论吗
No wild theories about the military industrial complex?
我不愿相信我们的国家会做这种事
I just don't want to believe my country could do something like this.
我也是
Me neither.
贝克特探长  卡塞尔先生
Detective Beckett, Mr. Castle.
欢迎来到蒙德堡
Thank you for visiting Fort Drummond.
我们了解到你们认为
So we gather that you believe
发生在市内的这个事件
that there was an incident that occurred in the city--
不是事件  是谋杀案  无人机袭击
No, not an incident. A murder, from a drone strike.
这种论断太过分了  探长
That's an outrageous accusation, detective.
你有什么证据
What do you base it on?
在犯罪现场搜集到的物证
Forensic evidence at the crime scene.
说明爆炸物是由无人机发射的导弹
It's consistent with a drone-fired missile.
今天上午共有多少无人机出行
How many drones were in the air this morning?
那是机密信息
That information is classified.
福蒂斯上校  上午8点15分
Colonel Fortis, was there a drone
是否有无人机飞过纽约上空
flying over New York City at 8:15 a.m.?
那也是机密信息
That's classified.
这样问吧
Okay, how about this?
还有谁有权操纵无人机吗
Did anyone else have access to the drones,
比如说联邦机构或者公司
any federal agencies, corporations?
-那是  -机密信息
- That's- - classified.
既然如此  那我想看看你们的飞行日志
Okay, well, then I'd like to take a look at your flight log.
这次会面结束了
This meeting is over.
记住
Keep in mind,
你们签的弃权声明书禁止你们
the waivers you signed prohibit you
讨论我们这次的谈话
from discussing what was said here.
你们什么都没说
Nothing was said here.
那我们就相安无事了
Well, then we shouldn't have a problem.
说得好
Touche.
那个男人在犯罪现场出现过
That man over there. He was at the crime scene.
他是谁
Who is he?
是你的手下吗
Does he work for you?
别多此一问了
Don't bother.
那是机密信息
It's classified.
我不知道你们在搞什么鬼
You know, I don't know what the hell you guys are up to,
但我保证  我一定会查清楚的
but I promise you, I will find out.
也许现在该说说
Now might be the time
疯狂的军工企业阴谋论了
for wild military industrial complex theories.
听听这个
And here's one--
坦纳打算发布绝密的军事文件
Tanner was about to post super-secret military documents.
他们派一架无人机将其灭口  现在在掩盖真相
They took him out with a drone, and now they're covering it up,
这也不算太疯狂啦
which actually isn't so wild.
我不知道
I don't know.
也许他们是不小心发射了导弹
Maybe they just... fired the missile by mistake.
那枚导弹碰巧击中了
And just so happened to hit
对美国政府直言不讳的批评家吗
a-a vocal critic of the U.S. government?
出现在犯罪现场的男人
And the guy from the crime scene
又正好出现在那场卡夫卡式的会面上吗
shows up at our kafkaesque meeting?
我觉得没这么巧
I don't think so.
我都不知道他们为什么要和我们面谈
I don't even know why they took that meeting.
他们什么信息都不给我们
All they did was stonewall.
接到了鉴证组来电
Yo. Got a call from C.S.U.
联邦警察刚才来拿走了
The feds just came in and seized all materials
一切与坦纳案子有关的资料
related to the Tanner case.
什么  那爆炸残留物和碎片样本呢
What, the explosive residue, the fragment samples?
-都拿走了  -我们被耍了
- All of it. - We've been played.
他们和我们见面只是为了查明
They just met with us to find out
物证在哪里以及我们知道些什么
where everything was and what we knew.
然后他们取走了所有证据
And then they grabbed all the evidence.
现在我们无法证明有一场无人机袭击
Yeah, and now we have no proof that a drone strike ever happened.
我们依然不清楚谋杀的原因
And we're no closer to figuring out why it happened
以及凶手是谁
or who did it.
也许坦纳的搭档能告诉我们
Well, maybe Tanner's partner could tell us.
你知道那是谁吗
Do you know who it is?
原来坦纳在东区大学
Turns out Tanner taught law classes
教授法律来维持生计
at East Borough College to make ends meet,
他的同事们说记得在大学附近
and his colleagues said they remember seeing
看到过他之前的学生奥马·迪克逊
a former student named Omar Dixon hanging around.
我询问了奥马的女友
I talked to Omar's girlfriend.
她说他的确为坦纳工作
She said that he did work for Tanner,
但他的工作都是秘密
but it was all hush-hush what he did.
奥马现在在哪里
And where's Omar now?
他女友说她不清楚
The girlfriend said she has no idea.
但是肖恩·坦纳可能知道
But Sean Tanner might.
他也在东区大学读书
He attends East Borough, too.
他曾经去学校和他爸见面
Used to drop by and see his dad.
也许他认识奥马
Maybe he knows Omar.
我觉得他确实认识
Oh, I think he does.
你记得当我们询问
You remember what he did
他是否知道他爸爸的搭档时  他做了什么吗
when you asked if he knew his dad's partner?
-他转移了话题  -正解
- He changed the subject. - Boom.
我告诉你  我不认识他
I'm telling you, I don't know him.
我不认识什么奥马·迪克逊
I don't know anyone named Omar Dixon.
肖恩  我知道执法部门
Look, Sean, I know that law enforcement
不总是站在你们一边
hasn't always been on your guys' side.
是从来都没有过
Try never.
但我们不是联调局  肖恩
But we're not the feds, Sean.
我们是想侦破你爸的谋杀案的警察
We're the guys trying to solve your dad's murder.
不管你怎么想
And no matter what you think,
我们没查出真凶就决不罢休
we're not gonna stop until that job is done.
告诉你  小弟
Here's the thing, bro--
如果你爸是因为他发布到网站上的资料而被谋杀
If your dad was killed for what he put on that web site,
那你哥们奥马也一样有危险
your boy Omar's in danger, too.
帮帮我们  肖恩
Help us out, Sean.
好吧  我见过奥马
Yeah, I met Omar.
我对他有些了解  他和我爸一起工作
I knew him a little. He worked with my dad.
他在哪里
Where can we find him?
我爸爸给了我他的电话
My dad gave me a number for him.
你得打给奥马
We need you to call that number,
告诉他你想和他见面
tell Omar you'd like to meet.
奥马
Omar?
什么  肖恩呢
Whoa. Where's-- where's Sean?
他来不了
He couldn't make it.
我得问你几个有关戴尔·坦纳的问题
Need to ask you a few questions about Dale Tanner.
我不要被牵扯进来
I'm not getting involved.
奥马  你已经身陷其中了
Omar, you're already involved.
那我不要越陷越深了
Well, then I'm not getting any more involved.
我在新闻中看到他的车被炸就已经够糟糕的了
It's bad enough I saw his blown-up car on the news.
现在也有人跟踪我
Now I've got people following me.
不止是你
And not just you.
什么人
What people?
女士  我不知道他们是谁
I have no idea, lady. No idea who they are.
谁杀的坦纳
Who killed Tanner?
是因为他打算发布的文件吗
Was it because of the documents that he was gonna post?
我他妈怎么知道
How the hell should I know?
你是他的搭档啊
You're his partner, aren't you?
他的搭档  人们是这么觉得的吗
His partner? Is that what people think?
所以他们才来跟踪我
Is that why they're after me?
如果你不是他的搭档
If you're not his partner,
那你是谁
then who are you?
他的助手  我是他的IT兼职工
His assistant. I'm his part-time I.T. Guy.
我建立他的网站  他给我文件
I set up his web site. He gave me files.
我将其上传  就这样
I'd upload them, and for that,
那个混蛋每小时付我15块
the cheap bastard paid me 15 bucks an hour.
他告诉过你他在忙活什么吗
Did he tell you what he was working on?
我不知道  也不关心
I didn't know and I didn't care.
对我来说只是一份兼职
It was just a gig for me,
现在  我都后悔我接下这份活儿了
and right now, I'm sorry I ever took it.
不许动
Don't move.
就是他  就是跟踪我的人之一
That's him. That's one of the guys that was following me.
奥马
Omar!
不许动
Steady.
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
作为随身携带消声手枪的人  他够冷静的
He's awfully calm for a guy walking around with a silenced pistol.
他之前也进过这样的房间
Yeah, well, he's been in rooms like this before.
我们对罗伯特·威廉姆斯有什么了解
So what do we know about Robert Williams?
他的身份是伪造的
That his I.D. is fake.
那他的指纹呢
What about his prints?
指纹系统里没有
There's no record of them in the system.
我不知道这家伙是谁
I don't know who this guy is.
我觉得
As is my way,
他是政府杀手
I'm gonna go with... government assassin.
那我们去一探究竟吧
Well, time to find out.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
这重要吗
Does it matter?
我们又不需要相互了解
It's not like we're gonna get to know each other.
谁杀了戴尔·坦纳
Who had Dale Tanner killed?
你参与了吗
Were you a part of it...
还是你的工作就是给人收拾烂摊子
or was your job just to clean up the mess?
你很固执
You're tenacious.
这我尊重
I respect that.
奥马·迪克逊也是需要被灭口的人吗
Was Omar Dixon a part of the mess?
他藏起来了
He went into hiding.
顺便问下  你是怎么把他找出来的
By the way, how did you manage to draw him out?
我提问  你回答
I'll be asking the questions.
我不会回答的
You just won't be getting the answers.
咱们走着瞧
We'll see.
我能扣留你24小时
I can keep you for 24 hours,
我也很愿意这么做
and I fully intend to do so.
你最多能扣留我五秒钟
You have me for five more seconds.
想想怎么利用这五秒吧
Use them well.
贝克特  有你的电话
Beckett, you got a phone call.
时间到
Time's up.
我是凯特·贝克特探长
This is detective Kate Beckett.
等等  什么  谁要接电话
I'm sorry. What? Hold for who?
晚上好  司法部长
Uh, good evening, Mr. Attorney General.
是  我是
Yes, it is.
是  我们把人扣留了
Yes, we do.
放了他  我...
Release him? I...
先生  恕我直言
Look, sir, with all due respect,
有人被谋杀  他是嫌疑人
a man has been killed, and he is a person of interest.
好吧  但有条件
Fine. But then I'm gonna want something in return.
是的
Yes, sir.
完全明白  非常感谢
I fully understand. Thank you, sir.
好手段  贝克特探长
Well played, detective Beckett.
你想知道什么
So... what do you want to know?
先说说你是谁吧
Why don't we start with, who are you?
杰瑞德·斯塔克
Jared Stack.
司法部长办公室特别调查员
Special investigator for the attorney general's office.
从没听过
I've never heard of it.
那是应该的
You're not supposed to.
你跟戴尔·坦纳有什么关系
And what's you connection to Dale Tanner?
坦纳本来正在被联调局
Tanner was under scrutiny
国土安全部  五角大楼的监视
by the FBI, D.H.S., and the Pentagon,
更别说纽约警局反恐部了
not to mention the NYPD counterterrorism unit.
需要有合适的人来调查他的死亡
Somebody objective needed to look into his death,
所以他们选了我
so they picked me.
你什么时候知道他不是死于汽车炸弹
When did you realize that he was killed by a drone
而是无人机袭击
and not a car bomb?
我们的人检查了车的残骸之后
Once our people examined the wreckage.
为什么要造假身份证
Why the fake I.D.?
我不懂问这些有什么用
I didn't know where this was headed.
司法部长需要明哲保身
The A.G. needs deniability.
"部长会宣称对你的行动一无所知"
"The secretary will disavow all knowledge of your actions."
《碟中谍》台词
It's "Mission: Impossible."
差不多吧  我还戴着人皮面具呢
Pretty much. I'm even wearing a mask.
-真的吗  -假的
- Really? - No.
你说你不懂我们问这些有什么用
You claim that you have no idea where this is headed,
但我觉得情况很明了
but it seems pretty clear to me.
军方对坦纳发起了袭击
The military launched an attack against Tanner.
我看了蒙德堡的日志
I went over the logs at Fort Drummond.
无人机不是那里来的
It didn't come from there.
那是哪里的
Where did it come from?
我也在查这个
That's what I'm trying to find out.
事实上  我们失去了很多无人机
The fact is, we've lost a number of drones.
一些落入了敌人手里
Some of 'em have fallen into enemy hands.
那么是我们一个敌人用无人机杀了坦纳吗
So one of our enemies killed Tanner with a drone?
这理论极不可能
That theory is highly improbable,
我都不买账  这很能说明问题
and coming from me, that's saying something.
这么说吧
Think of it this way--
政府要是真想杀了坦纳
Let's say our government wanted Tanner dead.
为什么不直接把他击毙在街头
Why not just gun him down in the streets?
为什么还出动无人机
Why use a drone?
为什么要选一个后患无穷的方式杀了他
Why get rid of him in a way that could bounce back on them?
跟大多数凶手的理由相同
The same reason most killers do--
以为能逃脱罪责
'cause they think they're gonna get away with it.
斯塔克
Stack.
什么
What?
你确定吗
You're sure?
好吧  给我发个链接
All right. Uh... send me a link to that feed.
谢了
Thanks.
怎么了
What is it?
是我的一个同事
That was one of my colleagues.
无人机不是蒙德堡派出的
The drone wasn't from Fort Drummond,
但飞机确实是我们的
but it was one of ours.
这是今早8点16分
This is the video feed
锡拉丘兹附近的空中国民警卫队基地
off a drone on a routine training run from an
派出的一架无人机进行例行训练时拍到的监控录像
Air National Guard Base near Syracuse at 8:16 this morning.
能把百叶窗关上吗
Would you mind shutting those blinds?
谁在控制飞机
Who's flying the drone?
问得好
Funny you should ask.
九分钟前驾驶员在长岛上空失去了对飞机的控制
The pilot lost control nine minutes earlier over Long Island.
什么叫失去了控制
Whoa. What do you mean, lost control?
自己听吧
Take a listen for yourself.
我也不知道  长官
I don't know, sir.
飞机对任何指令都没反应
It's not responding to any commands.
好吧  试试重启通讯软件
Okay, try rebooting the comm software.
已经重启了  也不管用
I already rebooted. That didn't fix it.
我们要不要通知交管局...
Do we need to notify T.S.A. that--
等等  那是什么情况
Wait. What the hell is that?
你对那辆车启用目标程序了吗
Are you running a targeting protocol on that vehicle?
没有  我什么都没做
No. I'm not doing anything.
我也不知道怎么回事
I don't know what's happening.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
有人黑进了无人机系统
Somebody hacked into that drone
干掉了戴尔·坦纳
and took out Dale Tanner.
这事没这么难以置信吧
Why is it so hard to believe?
常有人黑进银行系统
People hack into banks all the time--
五角大楼  美国宇航局什么的
the Pentagon, NASA.
是  但黑进无人机系统吗
Yeah, but a drone?
可能驾驶员在假装他控制不了了
Maybe the pilot was just pretending that he wasn't flying.
不对  那种惊慌失措没法假装
No, no. You can't fake that kind of panic.
我同意  他当时都要吓尿了
I agree. He was having a pants-soiling moment.
但我们忽略了一个可能性
But there is one possibility we are neglecting.
无人机本身
The drone itself.
就像《终结者3  机器人起义》
It's "Rise of the machines",
一如《终结者1》里的天网系统
not unlike skynet in "The terminator".
机器本身产生了意识
The machines have achieved consciousness,
他们怒气冲天
and they are pissed.
卡塞尔先生  抱歉让你失望了
Sorry to disappoint, Mr. Castle,
但我们要追查的是人类杀手
but it's a human perp we're after.
国家安全局拦截了一串
N.S.A. picked up an encrypted signal
驾驶员失去控制那一刻发送出去的加密信号
that was sent out the exact moment the pilot lost control.
这个信号覆盖了主控
That signal basically overrode the controls
使得黑客能控制无人机
and allowed the hacker to take over the drone.
信号来自哪里
And where did this signal come from?
来自纽约州下半部分
From the lower half of the state of New York.
国家安全局正在缩小范围
Uh, N.S.A. is trying to narrow that down as we speak.
这么说  我们可能正在找一个
So for all we know, we're looking for
14岁的电脑宅男吗
some 14-year-old nerd with a computer?
不太可能  这个黑客需要
No, it's not likely. Whoever did this
知道如何破解信号加密
had to know how to defeat the signal encryption
并拥有驾驶无人机的软件
and have the software to run the drone.
沃伯格
Warburg.
沃伯格是什么
What's a Warburg?
不是什么  是一个人
No, it's not a what. It's a who.
他是唯一能做到这些的人
He's the only guy that could've pulled this off.
我们该怎么找到他
Okay, how do we find him?
他销声匿迹已经有一年之久
He's been off-grid for about a year.
这家伙是个鬼魂  你们找不到他
The guy's a real ghost. You'll never find him.
我也许能通过追查这个信号找到他
But you know what? I might by tracing this signal.
也许我们可以合作
Maybe we can work on this together.
我同意告诉你们一些事
I agreed to tell you what I knew,
我已经做到了
which I've done.
合作愉快  贝克特探长
It's been real fun, Detective Beckett,
但是  从现在起  有我接手
but, uh, I'll take things from here, all right?
我还以为我们相处得很融洽呢
And here I thought we all had bonded.
如果沃伯格侵入了无人机系统
If Warburg hacked that drone,
他就是我们的嫌疑人
then he's our murder suspect,
我不会相信斯塔克的鬼话  说我们找不到他
and I am not buying Tack's word that we can't find him.
把他找出来  看看是个什么样的人
Let's dig into this guy and see who we're dealing with.
西蒙·沃伯格  编程界的传奇
Simon Warburg-- a programming legend.
克服了严重的强迫症
Overcame severe O.C.D. to become
成为了军用无人机操作软件的
chief designer for the operational software
首席设计师
used in military drones.
然后呢
And then what?
他被发现破坏那个软件
Well, he got busted for sabotaging that software.
在联调局抓他之前就跑了
But he fled before the FBI could arrest him.
沃伯格
Warburg.
听起来很像007里的大反派  对不
Sounds like a Bond villain, right?
制定统治世界的计划时
Petting his cat while formulating a plan
轻轻地爱抚小猫
for world domination.
你会问是什么计划
And what is that plan, you ask?
-我没问  -我问他们俩
- Actually, I didn't ask. - Talkin' to the boys.
建设一个无人机军队
To create a drone army--
一个可以思考  有意识的无人机军队
a drone army... that can think, that possess awareness.
哪有比设计系统给予它们生命的天才
And who better than the programming genius
更适合组建这支军队呢
who designed their software to give them that spark of life?
卡塞尔  你不会以为那是真的吧
Castle, you don't actually believe that.
记住  如果你说了是
And keep in mind, if you say yes,
我会觉得你没那么有魅力
I will find you less attractive.
很有可能啊
Well, it is conceivable,
我得说  这是非常合理的构思
and I have to say, a far better story.
看这个
Yo, check it.
沃伯格在躲起来之前发过一段视频
Warburg posted a video just before he went into hiding.
人们不理解我为什么要篡改
People don't understand why I tampered with
无人机软件
the drone software.
这就是沃伯格  我还以为会是...
That's Warburg? I was expecting...
邪恶博士吗
Dr. Evil?
不这么书呆子气的人
Someone a little less nerdy.
因为我预见到了未来的情况
It's because I've seen the future.
我知道他们的计划
And I know their plan.
要来了  肯定是组建无人机军队
Here it is. Building a drone army.
他们会引入侦察机
They'll introduce surveillance drones
监视交通状况
to monitor traffic.
看起来无害  对吗
Seems harmless enough, right?
所以我们不会有异议
So we let it happen.
紧接着  就会有安保无人机
Next, there'll be security drones.
因为谁不想更有安全感一点呢
Because who doesn't like to feel safer?
然后会有武装无人机保护我们的领空
And then armed drones to protect our skies.
那时候  就太晚了
And by then, it's too late.
因为可执行监视  控制
Because the system to monitor,
随时可杀人的系统
to control, to kill any one of us
已经建好了
will already be in place.
必须有人来阻止这一切
Someone has to stop this.
哪怕这个人就是我
Even if that someone is me.
他不是在建无人机军队
He wasn't building a drone army.
他在阻止建这军队
He was preventing one from being built.
我猜的挺准
I was pretty close.
如果你的"准"指的是"恰好相反"
If by "close," you mean "opposite."
沃伯格认为无人机
Warburg believed that drones were gonna be used
会用来攻击美国公民
to target U.S. citizens.
所以他杀了一个激进主义分子戴尔·坦纳
That's why he killed an activist like Dale Tanner--
告诉大家未来就在眼前
to show us that the future was already here.
这家伙为了阻止这一切
This guy basically framed the government
陷害了政府
to try to stop drone use.
找到沃伯格  就找到了凶手
So we get Warburg, we're gonna get our killer.
我觉得我知道该怎么找
And I think I know how.
看那些书
Guys, look at those books.
都是自然科学类
All on science.
都是初版
All first editions.
那是《物种起源》
That's "The Origin of the Species."
所以呢
So?
他是藏书家
So he was a book collector.
有强迫症的藏书家
A book collector with O.C.D.
旧习难改啊
a habit like that would die hard.
我明早开始查古董书屋
I'll start checking antique bookstores in the morning
看看沃伯格有没有联系过他们
to see if Warburg contacted any of them.
没有坦克能让...
No tank is gonna get...
贝克特  起来  快走
Beckett, get up. We gotta go.
你真的被唬住了
You totally fell for it.
你以为这是《终结者3》吗
You acted like it was "Rise of the Machines."
我没有
No, I didn't.
我没把它当成《终结
That's--I didn't think it was "Rise of the--
如果真是杀人坦克  你早跑了
If that was actually a killer tank, you bailed.
我是去拿球棒来保护你
I went to get the bat to the protect you
来消除威胁啊
to eliminate the threat.
是吗
Really?
这有摄像头  卡塞尔  我看到了你的表情
There's a camera here, Castle. I saw the look on your face.
贝克特  抱歉这么晚打给你
Hey, Beckett. Sorry to call you so late.
我查到了点东西
But I think I got something.
莱恩  你还在局里干什么
Ryan, what are you doing at the precinct?
我在看各种古董书屋的网站
Well, I was looking at web sites of antique bookstores,
然后我查了一下伍德斯托克附近的
and I was checking out one near Woodstock,
我好像找到了一个规律
and I think I've noticed a pattern.
什么样的规律
What kind of a pattern?
根据这份库存清单
According to this inventory grid,
有家店在上个月同一天卖掉了七本书
The bookseller sold seven books on the same day last month.
而且这七本书
And I see all seven of those books
都在沃伯格的书架上
on one shelf of Warburg's bookcase.
要么是发生了不可能事件
Either that's a statistical impossibility or--
要么就是沃伯格在重新收藏
Or Warburg is rebuilding his book collection
书架上的书
one shelf at a time.
也就是说  他是在那家书店买的
Which would mean, he ordered books from this bookstore.
这种旧皮革和纸张的味道啊
Ah, that aroma-- old leather and moldering paper.
我宣布
It's official.
我喜欢这个地方
I love this place.
卡塞尔  看  是《斯道姆季节》
Castle, look. It's "Storm Season."
在大甩卖区
Oh. On the clearance table.
好感全无
And the love fades.
有什么需要我帮忙的吗
Uh, can I help you?
事实上  还真有
Yes, as a matter of fact, you can.
你认识这个人吗
Do you recognize this man?
我还真认识
Oh, yes, indeed.
这是史密斯先生
It's--it's Mr. Smith.
他是个很有眼光的藏书人
He's quite a discerning collector.
他从我这买了很多书
Uh, he's purchased quite a few books from us here.
叫史密斯  真有创意
Really, Smith? That's original.
你有他的地址吗  你们会送货上门吗
Do you have his address? Does he get his books delivered?
不  他都是自己来拿的
No, no. He comes in and he picks them up.
看见他开什么车吗
Do you know what kind of car he drives?
他一般是骑车
Well, he usually rides a bicycle.
他住在附近
So he's local.
我让他们两个查一下
All right. I'm gonna get the boys to look up
自从去年沃伯格消失之后
all the properties bought or sold in the area
这附近交易过的房产
over the past year, since Warburg went missing.
有没有搞错
Seriously?
这本书  很不错
Uh, it's--it's-- it's a nice book.
谢谢
Thank you.
据莱恩所说
So according to Ryan,
房子在这条车道的尽头
the house at the end of this driveway
十个月前通过代理人购买
was purchased ten months ago by attorney.
沃伯格就在这里
Warburg is here.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
卡塞尔  我们每到一个地方
Castle, you've said that
你都会这么说
about every place we've been to so far.
但这次我是说真的
Yeah, but this time I mean it.
这次的感觉特别强烈
The force is stronger with this one.
问题是  这里是私人领地
The problem is, it's private property,
我没有搜查令
and I don't have a warrant.
假装没看到标志就行了
Just pretend you don't see the sign.
听着  我们马上就要找到沃伯格了
Look, we're on the cusp of finding Warburg,
他至少是个嫌犯吧
who, at the very least, is a person of interest
至多可能是个超能力大反派
and at most, a maniacal super-villain
能用意念操控无人机
with the power to bend drones to his will.
然后
And...
门没锁
Gate's unlocked.
日头真毒
Burning daylight.
沃伯格可能就在这儿
Maybe Warburg is here.
这里偏远而且隐蔽
It is remote and secluded.
我又有个很不安的想法
You know, I just had a deeply disturbing thought.
就像你平时的那些想法吗
Much like most of your thoughts?
如果沃伯格与这事无关呢
What if Warburg isn't involved?
我是说  我们之前已经被耍过一次了
I mean... we have been played before.
如果斯塔克只是提到他的名字
What if Stack just mentioned his name
好让我们去白费力气
to send us on a wild-goose chase?
卡塞尔  我不这么认为
Oh, Castle, I don't think so.
反正沃伯格涉案的证据
Ah, still, there's no more proof that Warburg is involved
不比无人机智能自控多
than there is that the drone acted on its own.
没搞错吧  我难道还没把天网
Seriously? I haven't gotten that skynet thing
从你脑子里洗掉吗
out of your system yet?
你可以嘲笑我  但记住我的话
You mock me, but mark my words.
会有那么一天的
The day will come.
科学家们称之为奇点
The experts call it the singularity...
科技超级智能的出现
the emergence of a technological super intelligence--
慢着  卡塞尔  等等
Wait, Castle. Wait. Wait.
你听到了吗
Wait. Do you hear that?
像是嗡嗡声
Like a buzzing.
你还好吗
You okay?
还好
Yeah, I think so.
这就像是《西北偏北》里演的那样
Hey, that was just like "North by Northwest."
卡塞尔  别激动过头了  它又回来了
Castle, don't get too excited. It's coming back.
你在干什么  我们应该逃啊
What are you doing? We gotta run.
没时间找掩体了
We're never gonna make it to cover.
它一旦进入射程  我就开枪
As soon as it gets in range, I'm gonna shoot it.
好吧
Okay.
好吧好吧
Okay. Okay. Okay.
难以置信  你竟然没一发命中
I can't believe you missed with every shot.
搞笑呢吧
Really?!
你以为是你把这无人机射下来的吗
Do you think that you shot down that drone
就你这点枪法
with your marksmanship?
我刚才挺身而出
I rose to the occasion.
这回
Wow, this time,
我真的保护了你
I really did protect you.
是啊  还保护了你自己
Yeah, along with yourself.
这弥补了所谓的
You know, this makes up for what may be considered
男子气概的短暂缺失
a momentary lack of manliness.
不  我已经获得了救赎
No, I have earned my redemption.
谁都抢不走
Nothing can take that away from me.
这些不是真的子弹  是空弹
These aren't real bullets. These are blanks.
空弹
Blanks?
我事先不知道
Well, I didn't know that,
所以这不能
so that doesn't--
不能消减我的英雄行为
that doesn't diminish the act of heroism.
真的是空弹吗
That-- are those really blanks?
当然是空弹  你们两个笨蛋
Of course they're blanks, you idiot.
这是为了阻止你们这些闯入者
Meant to deter trespassers like you.
你刚才消灭了我最出色的一架无人机
You just obliterated my finest drone.
我要找警察逮捕你们
I'm having the cops arrest you.
那我给你省电话费了
Let me save you a phone call.
我们是为了戴尔·坦纳来的
We're here about Dale Tanner,
沃伯格先生
Mr. Warburg.
就知道有人会找来
Knew somebody would be eventually.
看看四螺旋桨直升机  我的最爱
Check out the quad. It's my favorite.
酷毙了
Oh, sweet.
毁掉我无人机的报应
Payback for wrecking my drone.
沃伯格先生
Mr. Warburg,
说说戴尔·坦纳吧
let's talk about Dale Tanner.
你想知道是不是我杀了他
You want to know if I killed him.
答案是  是的  是我做的
The answer is, yes, I did.
能告诉我为什么吗
Would you like to tell me why?
这要从两年前说起
It began two years ago...
从这里说起
With this.
我不明白一辆车穿越沙漠的照片
I don't understand what a car driving through the desert
跟戴尔·坦纳有什么关系
has to do with Dale Tanner.
情报显示车里有三名
Intelligence reports said there were three
阿富汗高级武装分子
high-ranking Afghan militants in this car.
制造商和车型都匹配
It was the right make and model,
并在高速行驶
traveling at a high rate of speed.
所以无人机驾驶员得到了袭击信号
So the drone pilot was given the green light to strike.
但后来
But then...
他看到了车上的这些红点
he saw those red dots on the trunk...
就有一种预感
and he had a feeling
于是他终止了任务
so he aborted the mission.
车里并没有武装分子
There were no militants in that car.
红点其实是玫瑰花
The red dots were roses,
因为行驶在沙漠路上的
because the young couple driving down that desert road
是一对新婚夫妇
had just gotten married.
那时我才明白
That's when I knew I could no longer
我不能再搞无人机程序
be a part of the drone program.
我不明白  为什么
Uh, I don't understand. Why?
驾驶员没有射击
The pilot didn't fire.
因为新一代无人机不会配备驾驶员
Because the next generation of drones won't have pilots.
新的人工智能软件会赋予无人机
The new A.I. Software will give drones
决策能力
decision-making capability.
它们获取数据并执行致命行动
They'll assess the data and take lethal action
全靠它们自己
all on their own.
《终结者3》真正上演
It really will be "Rise of the Machines."
那些无人机会毫不犹豫地把那辆车
Those new drones would turn that car to ash
化为灰烬
without hesitation.
这就是为什么人命关天之际
That's why, when lives are at stake,
需要有人看到玫瑰花
we need a man who sees roses.
我们需要人为因素
We need the human factor.
你在杀害戴尔·坦纳的时候  人为因素去哪了
And where was the human factor when you killed Dale Tanner?
我给你们看个东西
Let me show you something.
这个程序是我写的
I wrote this program myself.
看看这个用户友好型界面
Note the user-friendly interface.
我的得意之作
I'm rather proud of it.
这些红点表示现在纽约上空的
Now these red dots are individual drones
几架无人机
currently over New York state.
如果我点击一架
Now if I click on one...
我就能实时监控无人机的运行
I can monitor the drone's function in real time.
按一下按钮
And with the push of a button,
我就能控制飞机
I can take over control of the aircraft.
就像你对坦纳做的那样
Just like you did with Tanner.
我那天正在骑车
Oh, I was on a bike ride that day
远离电脑
and nowhere near a computer.
你刚才还说是你杀了他
You just said that you killed him.
我是指我的软件导致了他的死亡
Well, I meant my software led to his death,
但我没有杀他
but I didn't do it.
其实我在跟戴尔·坦纳联系
In fact, I was in touch with Dale Tanner.
我想让他公布这个程序
I wanted him to post the program.
所以我把软件载在闪存盘里给了他
So I loaded it onto a flash drive and got it to him.
你想坦纳把你的黑客软件
You wanted Tanner to post
发布到他的网站上
your drone-hacking software on his web site?
如果军方发现了
If the Pentagon found out,
他们就会不得不禁飞所有无人机
they'd have to ground their entire drone fleet.
没错
Precisely.
这会逼停无人机的研发工作
It'd bring drone development to a grinding halt.
但坦纳拒绝把软件发布到网上
But Tanner refused to post the program.
他把它发了回来
He sent it back,
他说不想让任何有电脑傻子
saying he didn't want any idiot with a computer
都能随便操纵无人机
being able to take over control of a drone.
我觉得他说的在理
I realized he might have a point,
就决定自己留着
so, um, I decided to keep the program to myself.
那如果你没用  坦纳也没有发布到网上
So if you didn't use this and Tanner didn't post it,
那是谁杀了他呢
then who killed him?
我得知他的死之后
After I heard about his death,
我检查了我寄给他的闪存盘
I checked out the flash drive I sent him.
发现有人把我的软件
Someone copied my program off of it
拷进了U盘
onto a usb drive.
肯定不是坦纳拷的
Now it wasn't Tanner.
因为他不会去操纵无人机炸自己
He wouldn't order a drone strike on himself.
也不会是我这方面的人  因为
And it wasn't anyone on my end, because, well...
我就一个人
who else is there?
这么说  肯定是坦纳身边的人
So then it had to be someone close to Tanner
此人能够接触到他的工作
with access to his work.
只有一个人能办得到
And we only know one person like that.
他的助手奥马·迪克逊
His assistant-- Omar Dixon.
我猜是这么回事
Okay, here's my theory--
奥马·迪克逊在为坦纳工作
Omar Dixon is working for Tanner,
但他生活十分拮据
but he's just scraping by.
然后得知了沃伯格的黑客软件
Along comes Warburg's drone hack.
坦纳不想要
Tanner doesn't want it.
但迪克逊却看到了商机
But Dixon sees an opportunity.
他觉得一个能操控无人机的黑客软件
He realizes how much a drone-hacking program
肯定值不少钱
would be worth on the open market.
没错  他拷贝下来  学会了使用方法
Exactly. He burns a copy, learns how to use it.
下一步就是  实地操作
The next step-- real-world test.
既然坦纳是个王八蛋  那正好
And Tanner's a cheap bastard anyway, so...
我来接
I'll get it.
找理查德·卡塞尔  请按1
For Richard Castle, press 1.
找贝克特  请按2
For Beckett, press 2.
我就直接说了  你个蠢蛋
Yo. How about I just talk, jackass?
我们通缉了奥马·迪克逊
So we put out an A.P.B. on Omar Dixon,
但他似乎早就听到了风声
but it looks like he's already in the wind.
他女友说他打好包袱
His girlfriend said that he packed a bag,
走消防楼梯跑了
snuck out down the fire escape.
把他的照片贴到机场
Okay, circulate his photo to airports
公交站和火车站
and bus and train stations.
已经在办了
Already on it.
贝克特警探  我很感谢你
Detective Beckett, I sure do appreciate you
帮我找到西蒙·沃伯格
finding Simon Warburg for me.
你告诉我们他的名字时就是这么期望的吧
Is that what you were hoping for when you gave us his name?
我只是觉得
Well, I just thought
你们可能会想到我们没想到的地方
you might think of something that we hadn't.
在我定位你手机时
When I pinged your cell phone,
我发现我是对的
I realized I was right.
联邦调查局已经去缉拿他了
FBI's picking him up right now.
有件事你可能会感兴趣  坦纳不是他杀的
Well, then it might interest you to know he didn't kill Tanner.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
我们觉得凶手是奥马·迪克逊
We have reason to believe that it was Omar Dixon,
他是坦纳的助手
Tanner's assistant.
问题是  他逃跑了
The problem is, he's on the run.
这事我能帮忙
I can help with that.
面部识别系统正在扫描
The facial recognition system's scanning footage
过去两小时各大交通枢纽的监控录像
over the last two hours from all the main departure points.
这东西有多精准
How accurate is this thing, really?
只要他在摄像头前经过
Well, if he passed in front of one of those cameras,
就能找到他
it'll spot him.
堪比《1984》里的"老大哥"
Man, talk about Big Brother.
但还是有办法能躲过这系统  对吧
There's gotta be a way to beat the system, though, right?
戴副大墨镜
Wear big sunglasses,
用刘海遮住脸
let your bangs hang down over your forehead.
这样就能蒙混过关
It totally messes with the software.
万一没刘海怎么办
What if you don't have bangs?
可以化浓妆
You could wear heavy makeup.
把脸搽得五颜六色的
Paint random-colored shapes all over your face.
我才不干这种事
Yeah, I'm not doing that.
找到他了
And there he is.
92分钟前在肯尼迪机场的国际候机楼  找到了
J.F.K., International Terminal, 92 minutes ago. We got him.
现在它会根据脸部
Now it'll track him off his face
还有衣服颜色来追踪他
and the color of his clothes.
该死
Damn it.
奥马·迪克逊上了去贝鲁特的飞机
Omar Dixon caught a flight to Beirut.
一小时前起飞了
Left an hour ago.
他跑了
He's gone.
我们联系了航空公司
We reached the airline.
奥马·迪克逊确实上了去贝鲁特的航班
Omar Dixon was definitely on that flight to Beirut,
-经阿联酋中转  -去贝鲁特干嘛
- By way of Abu Dhabi. - Why beirut?
他母亲那边的亲戚在那儿
He's got family there on his mom's side
而且有双重国籍
and dual citizenship.
他出境用的黎巴嫩护照
He flew out on a Iebanese passport.
能在他降落后扣押他吗
Can we have him detained when he lands?
不行  我们和黎巴嫩没有引渡条约
No. There's no extradition agreement.
也许他就是去那的原因
Probably why he went there.
而且在那里卖这黑客软件
And it's an excellent part of the world
绝对会非常抢手
if you want to sell some drone-hacking software.
说到黑客软件
Speaking of drone hacking...
来认识一下奥马·迪克逊吧
Say hello to our friend Omar Dixon.
回头见了  奥马
See you later, Omar.
我还以为他正飞往贝鲁特
I thought he was heading to Beirut.
我找了司法部长
He was until I asked the attorney general
他联系了航空局
to contact the F.A.A.
把航班召回了肯尼迪机场
And have them recall the flight back to J.F.K.
哥上头有人  关系够硬
You know, one of the perks of working
办事就是方便
for an 800-pound gorilla.
你们审问他了吗
Did you already interview him?
这个嘛
Well...
全靠你  我们才逮住了他
You're the reason we got him, Detective Beckett.
他就听你发落吧
Why don't you do the honors?
瞧瞧她
Look at that...
看她审讯的手法多老道
How she uses the silence.
她是一股不可阻挡的动力
She's a force to be reckoned with.
你还不算真正见识到呢
Oh, you don't know the half of it.
奥马  我们正在你的行李里搜寻一个U盘
Omar, right now, your bags are being searched for a usb drive.
你最好的出路  就是趁早向我坦白
Your best bet is to tell me the truth before it turns up.
我已经坦白了
I told you the truth.
我跟坦纳的死没有关系
I had nothing to do with what happened to Tanner.
那你为什么要逃往国外
Then why did you flee the country?
因为我想活命
Because I like being alive, that's why.
有人在他车上装了炸弹  他们在追杀我
Somebody put a bomb in his car. I had people chasing me.
你我都知道根本没有炸弹
You and I both know that there was no bomb.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你用软件操纵了无人机
You used the software hack
发射了一枚导弹
to fire a missile from a drone.
你胡说什么
You're outta your mind.
我为什么要这么做
Wh-why is this happening to me?!
你打算告诉我你对沃伯格
Are you actually gonna sit there and tell me that you had no idea
给坦纳的闪存盘一无所知吗
about the flash drive Warburg gave Tanner?
我当然略知一二
I had an idea, sure.
坦纳派我去情报传递点取回U盘
Tanner sent me to pick it up from the dead drop.
你什么时候拷的软件
At which time, you copied it.
我什么都没拷
I never copied anything.
我连里面是什么都不知道
I didn't even know what was on it.
第二天  坦纳说他不要了
The next day, Tanner said he didn't want it,
于是他派我把闪存盘
and so he--he told me to return the flash drive
送回情报传递点
to the dead drop.
我就干了这些  没别的
So that's what I did. That's all I did.
还有人知道优盘的事
Did anyone else know about the flash drive
或者能拿到优盘吗
or have access to it?
有
Yeah.
只有一个人
Yeah, just one person.
你好  肖恩
Hey, Sean.
我们能进去吗
You mind if we come in?
进来吧
I guess.
你妈妈呢  肖恩
Where's your mom, Sean?
她去买东西了  怎么了
She went to get groceries. What's up?
有关于我爸爸的消息吗
Is there news about my dad?
我们和奥马谈过了
We talked to Omar.
他说你两个月前开始到办公室去
He said you started dropping by the office two months ago,
通常都是你爸爸不在的时候
Mostly when your dad wasn't around.
我喜欢跟奥马待在一起  那又怎样
I like hanging with Omar. So what?
你其实是想跟你父亲联络感情吧
Or was it to connect with your dad?
两个月前正是他搬出去的时候  不是吗
I mean, two months ago, that's when he moved out, isn't it?
我不是很明白
Okay, uh, I-- I'm not exactly sure
我们为什么要谈这些
why we're talking about this.
你去他教科的大学
Is that why you went to the college
也是因为这个吗
where he taught classes,
跟他联络感情
so you could connect?
肖恩  你的生活一定不容易
I mean, it had to be hard, Sean,
有那样一位父亲
having a father like that--
总是不在家  对工作如此地投入
so absent, so driven.
这个革命者把自己的使命看得
A crusader who put his mission above all else, even...
比亲人还重要
the people who loved him.
沃伯格的无人机操纵程序被存在一个4G的U盘里
Warburg's drone hack was copied on to a 4-gig usb drive.
程序被拷贝那天你恰好拿着一个
Just so happens you bought the same kind of drive
同样的优盘
the day that copy was made.
你给你父亲打了个电话
You called your dad.
你让他跟你见面
You asked him to meet with you
因为你想知道他的具体位置
because you wanted to know exactly where he would be.
不是吗  肖恩
Isn't that right, Sean?
是什么导致你走上不归路  肖恩
So what pushed you over the edge, Sean?
是在你发现他出轨之后吗
Was it when you found out about the affair?
我和我妈妈相依为命
My mom... held us together.
爸爸总是不在
Dad was always gone.
我们一直没有钱
We never had any money.
而且总是被监视着
We were being watched all the time.
因为所有的流言蜚语我们也没有朋友
No friends because of all the rumors and whispers.
就是这样
And that was it.
这就是我们的生活
That was our life.
这样他可以揭露恶行
All so he could expose wrongdoing
逼迫当局对这些行为负责
and hold the authorities accountable.
但他的家庭怎么办
What about his family?
为什么我们还没有那些愚蠢的丑闻重要
Why didn't we matter as much as some stupid scandal?
在做了这些事之后
And then, after all of it,
在他让我们经历了这么多痛苦之后
after everything that he put us through,
他抛弃我妈妈找了另一个女人
He leaves my mom for another woman?!
你想让他付出代价
And you wanted to make him pay.
他伤了她的心
He broke her heart!
还伤了我
Me...
他也伤了我的心
He broke mine, too.
这是怎么了  发生什么事了
What is this? What's going on?
回我家之后来一杯
How about a nice glass of zinfandel
馨芳葡萄酒怎么样
when we get back to my place?
在经历了今天这些事之后  这是个好主意
After the day we've had today, that sounds great.
贝克特探长  卡塞尔先生
Detective Beckett and Mr. Castle,
总统和司法部长让我传达
Both the president and the Attorney General
他们的谢意
have asked me to convey their thanks
因为付出的努力
for your work on this case.
我想总统的赞扬没法
I don't suppose the president's appreciation
以推荐词的形式出现在我的书上吧
could come in the form of a blurb for my book?
对  那不可能
Yeah, that's not gonna happen.
但是
Uh, but,
贝克特探长  我能跟你单独谈谈吗
Detective Beckett, could I have a word?
好吧
Yeah.
我想问你件事
Let me ask you something.
你觉得五年之后的你是什么样
Where do you see yourself five years from now?
我还没有想过这个问题
I haven't really given it much thought.
当警督  还是警监
As a lieutenant, a captain?
在警察系统中一步步往上爬吗
At one police plaza climbing the ladder?
那些不是我心之所向
That's not really where my heart is.
你的心在哪儿  那个房间里吗
Where is your heart... in that room?
五年后你还想继续待在那里
You want to be in that room five years from now,
继续抓那些杀人犯吗
busting some killer's balls?
我跟你不熟
I don't know you.
绝对没熟到谈这个话题的程度
Certainly not well enough to have this conversation.
我曾经也也在谋杀案组待过
Yeah, I used to work Homicide, too.
-真的吗  -对
- Really? - Yeah.
在芝加哥
Chicago.
直到有个人给了我另一份工作
Till some guy tapped me on the shoulder.
今天我就是那个人
Today, I'm that guy.
我想说的是
What I'm saying is this--
我觉得你非常出色
I think you're exceptional.
你聪明  坚强
You're smart, you're strong,
你能灵活地思考
You're an asymmetrical thinker.
你能成大事
I see bigger things for you.
谁说我想成大事了
Who says I want bigger things?
你身上的一切都在大喊想要成大事
Practically everything about you screams it.
特区刚好有个职位空缺
There's a job opening in D.C.
什么职位
What job?
在司法部长手下干
With the Attorney General.
我们直接向他汇报工作
We report directly to him.
我们在办大案要案的时候
We work with total autonomy
有完全的自主权
on the biggest, most challenging cases.
就像这个案子一样
Cases like this,
代价很高
where the stakes are high
而结果通常能改变历史
and the outcome can affect history.
不是每个人都能胜任那个职位
Not everybody has what it takes for the job.
我觉得你可以
I think you do.
打这个号码预约面试
Call that number to schedule an interview.
考虑一下
Think about it.
我会的
I will.
我会再跟你联络的  贝克特探长
I'll be talking to you, Detective Beckett.
你可以放轻松了  卡塞尔
So you can rest easy, Castle.
看起来机器的崛起
It looks like the rise of the machines
还要花几年时间
is still a few years off.
那架自主无人驾驶飞机就想让你这么想
That's what the autonomous drones want you to think.
事实是一架自主无人驾驶飞机
Well, the fact is, an autonomous drone
不可能杀死戴尔·坦纳
would never have killed Dale Tanner.
是的
Mm, true,
因为对人来说
Because with people,
所有的决定都是私人的
all decisions are personal.
有的人能看到玫瑰
And where one person might see roses...
有的人看到的却是摆脱旧生活
Another may see a chance to move on from an old life
开始新生活的机会
and on to a new one.
人为因素
The human factor.
我这个"人"要去洗澡了
And this human needs a shower.
一起来吗
Care to join me?
我马上就去
I'll be there in a minute.
你还没告诉我
You never did tell me
斯塔克想跟你聊什么呢
what Stack wanted to talk to you about.
没什么
Nothing.
不是什么大事
It was nothing.